If you want to buy high-quality, low-price cocaine,
إن كنت ترغب في شراء كوكايين بجودة عالية وسعرٍ زهيد،
there really is only one place to go,
فثمَّة مكانٌ وحيدٌ تذهب إليه،
and that is the dark net anonymous markets.
وهو أسواق الشبكة المظلمة المجهولة.
Now, you can't get to these sites
لا بمكنك الدخول إلى هذه المواقع
with a normal browser -- Chrome or Firefox --
من خلال متصفح عادي مثل (كروم ) أو (فَيرفكس )
because they're on this hidden part of the Internet,
لأنها في هذا الجانب الخفي من الإنترنت،
known as Tor hidden services,
المعروف باسم "خدمات تور الخفية"،
where URLs are a string of meaningless numbers and letters that end in .onion,
حيث الروابط عبارة عن سلسلة عقيمة من الأرقام و الحروف المنتهية بـ(onion)
and which you access with a special browser
تدخل إليها من خلال متصفحٍ خاص
called the Tor browser.
يُسمى متصفح (تور).
Now, the Tor browser was originally a U.S. Naval intelligence project.
كان متصفح تور في الأصل مشروع المخابرات البحرية الامريكية.
It then became open source,
وبعدها أصبح برنامجًا مفتوح المصدر،
and it allows anybody to browse the net
يسمح لأي شخص أن يتصفح الإنترنت
without giving away their location.
دون إظهار موقعه.
And it does this by encrypting your IP address
ويفعل ذلك من خلال تشفير عنوان آي بي الخاص بك
and then routing it via several other computers around the world
ومن ثم يوجهه عبر العديد من أجهزة الحاسوب الأخرى حول العالم
that use the same software.
التي تستخدم البرنامج ذاته.
You can use it on the normal Internet,
يمكنك استخدامه في التصفح العادي للإنترنت،
but it's also your key to the dark net.
ولكنه أيضًا مفتاحك إلى الشبكة المظلمة.
And because of this fiendishly clever encryption system,
وبسبب نظام التشفير شديد الذكاء هذا،
the 20 or 30 -- we don't know exactly -- thousand sites that operate there
فإن العشرين أو الثلاثين ألف موقع التي تُدار هناك -لا نعلم عددها تحديدًا-
are incredibly difficult to shut down.
يصعُب إغلاقها للغاية.
It is a censorship-free world visited by anonymous users.
فهو عالم بلا رقابة يزوره مستخدمون مجهولون.
Little wonder, then, that it's a natural place to go
فليس مدهشًا إذًا، أن يكون مكانًا طبيعيًا يذهب إليه
for anybody with something to hide,
أي شخص معه شيء يريد إخفاءه،
and that something, of course, need not be illegal.
وبالطبع، فإن هذا الشيء غير قانوني.
On the dark net, you will find
على الشبكة المظلمة، ستجد
whistle-blower sites, The New Yorker.
مواقع كاشفي الفساد، و مجلة (النيويوركر)،
You will find political activism blogs.
وستجد مدونات النشاط السياسي.
You will find libraries of pirated books.
وستجد مكتبات الكتب المقرصنة.
But you'll also find the drugs markets,
ولكنك ستجد أيضًا أسواق المخدرات،
illegal pornography, commercial hacking services,
وصور إباحية غير قانونية، وخدمات القرصنة التجارية،
and much more besides.
والكثير والكثير.
Now, the dark net is one of the most interesting, exciting places
لذا، فالشبكة المظلمة هي واحدة من أكثر الأماكن إثارةً وتشويقًا
anywhere on the net.
من أي مكانٍ آخر على الإنترنت.
And the reason is, because although innovation, of course,
والسبب في ذلك -مع ما فيها من إبتكار بالطبع،
takes place in big businesses,
هو أنها تحدث في الأعمال الكبيرة،
takes place in world-class universities,
وتحدث في أفضل جامعات العالم،
it also takes place in the fringes,
وتحدث أيضًا في الجماعات المهمشة،
because those on the fringes -- the pariahs, the outcasts --
لأن أولئك الأشخاص المهمشون والمنبوذون والمطرودون من بلادهم
they're often the most creative, because they have to be.
هم الأكثر إبداعًا غالبًا، لأنهم مضطرون لذلك.
In this part of the Internet,
في هذا الجانب من الإنترنت،
you will not find a single lolcat,
لن تجد صورة واحدة من صور القطط المضحكة،
a single pop-up advert anywhere.
ولن تجد أي إعلانٍ منبثق في أي مكان.
And that's one of the reasons why I think
وهذا واحدٌ من الأسباب التي أرى أنها
many of you here will be on the dark net fairly soon.
ستجعل الكثيرين منكم يدخلون إلى الشبكة المظلمة قريبًا جدًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Not that I'm suggesting anyone in this audience would use it
هذا لا يعني أني قترح على أحدٍ منكم أن يستخدم الشبكة
to go and procure high-quality narcotics.
في الحصول على مخدرات ذات نوعية ممتازة.
But let's say for a moment that you were.
ولكن لنقل للحظة كنت ستفعلها.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Bear with me.
أستميحكم عذرًا.
The first thing you will notice on signing up to one of these sites
أول ما ستلاحظونه عند التسجيل في أحد هذه المواقع
is how familiar it looks.
هو تشابهها الكبير.
Every single product --
فكل منتج
thousands of products --
-بل آلاف المنتجات-
has a glossy, high-res image,
لديه صورة لامعة عالية الجودة،
a detailed product description, a price.
ووصف مفصل عن المنتج، وسعره.
There's a "Proceed to checkout" icon.
ويوجد أيقونة "تفحص المنتج"
There is even, most beautifully of all,
والأجمل من كل هذا، أنه يوجد حتى
a "Report this item" button.
زر "بلغ عن هذا المنتج".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Incredible.
مذهل!
You browse through the site, you make your choice,
فأنت تبحر خلال الموقع، وتتخذ اختيارك،
you pay with the crypto-currency bitcoin,
وتدفع بالعملة المشفرة بيتكوين،
you enter an address -- preferably not your home address --
وتُدِخل عنوانًا -ويُفضل ألا يكون عنوان منزلك-
and you wait for your product to arrive in the post,
وتنتظر أن يصلك المنتج بالبريد،
which it nearly always does.
ودائمًا ما يصل.
And the reason it does is not because of the clever encryption.
السبب في ذلك ليس بسبب التشفير الذكي.
That's important.
هذا مهم.
Something far simpler than that.
وإنما أمرٌ أبسط من ذلك بكثير.
It's the user reviews.
إنه تقييم المستخدم.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You see, every single vendor on these sites
أترون، كل بائع في هذه المواقع
uses a pseudonym, naturally enough,
يستخدم اسمًا مستعارًا، هذا طبيبعي جدًا،
but they keep the same pseudonym to build up a reputation.
لكنهم يستمرون في استخدام الاسم المستعار نفسه لبناء السمعة.
And because it's easy for the buyer to change allegiance whenever they want,
ولأنه من السهل على المشتري أن يغير رأيه في أي وقتٍ شاء
the only way of trusting a vendor
فإن الطريقة الوحيدة للثقة في البائع
is if they have a good history of positive feedback
هي رؤية ما إذا كان لديه تاريخ جيد من التقييم الإيجابي
from other users of the site.
من المستخدمين الآخرين للموقع.
And this introduction of competition and choice
ومفهوم المنافسة والاختيار هذا
does exactly what the economists would predict.
فعل بالضبط ما تنبأه الاقتصاديون.
Prices tend to go down, product quality tends to go up,
إذ تنخفض الأسعار، وترتفع جودة المنتج،
and the vendors are attentive,
ويصبح البائعون لطفاء،
they're polite, they're consumer-centric,
ومهذبون، ويصبح المستهلك في أولوياتهم،
offering you all manner of special deals, one-offs,
ويعرضون جميع أنواع العروض الخاصة، والعروض الفريدة،
buy-one-get-one-frees, free delivery,
وشراء واحدة وأخذ الثانية مجانًا، والتوصيل المجاني،
to keep you happy.
كل ذلك لجعلك سعيدًا
I spoke to Drugsheaven.
تحدثت إلى (دراغز هيفين).
Drugsheaven was offering excellent and consistent marijuana
كان (دراغز هيفٍن) يعرض بانجو ممتازا وبحالة جيدة
at a reasonable price.
بسعرٍ معقول.
He had a very generous refund policy,
كان يعمل بسياسة إعادة المال،
detailed T's and C's,
شروط وأحكام مفصلة،
and good shipping times.
وأوقات شحن ملائمة.
"Dear Drugsheaven," I wrote,
" السيد المحترم دراغز هيفن" -هذا ما كتبته-
via the internal emailing system that's also encrypted, of course.
عبر نظام المراسلة الداخلي المشفر أيضًا بطبيعة الحال.
"I'm new here. Do you mind if I buy just one gram of marijuana?"
"أنا جديدٌ هنا. هل تمانع لو اشتريت جرامًا واحدًا فقط من البانجو؟"
A couple of hours later, I get a reply.
بعد ذلك بساعتين، تلقيت ردًا.
They always reply.
وهم دائمًا ما يردون.
"Hi there, thanks for your email.
"مرحبًا، شكرًا على رسالتك".
Starting small is a wise thing to do. I would, too, if I were you."
"البدء بجرعة صغيرة هو عين العقل . كنت سأفعل الأمر ذاته لو كنت مكانك."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"So no problem if you'd like to start with just one gram.
" لذا، فلا بأس إن كنت تريد البدء بجرامٍ واحدٍ فقط".
I do hope we can do business together.
"آمل أن نعقد صفقات عملٍ معًا".
Best wishes, Drugsheaven."
"مع أطيب التمنيات، (دراغز هيفِن)".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I don't know why he had a posh English accent, but I assume he did.
لا أعلم إن كان يتكلم بلهجة إنجليزية راقية، ولكني أفترض أنه فعل ذلك.
Now, this kind of consumer-centric attitude
هذا النوع من الموقف الحريص على المستهلك
is the reason why, when I reviewed 120,000 pieces of feedback
هو السبب في أنني عندما استعرضت 120 ألف تقييم
that had been left on one of these sites over a three-month period,
من التقييمات التي وٌضعت على أحد هذه المواقع خلال أكثر من ثلاثة أشهر،
95 percent of them were five out of five.
وجدت أن 95% من هذه التقييمات حاصلة على 5/5
The customer, you see, is king.
فكما ترون، العميل هو الملك.
But what does that mean?
ولكن ماذا يعني هذا؟
Well, on the one hand,
حسنًا، من ناحية،
that means there are more drugs, more available, more easily,
هذا يعني أنه يوجد المزيد من المخدرات، أكثر إتاحة وتيسيرًا،
to more people.
لمزيدٍ من الناس.
And by my reckoning, that is not a good thing.
وفي تقديري، هذا ليس أمرًا جيدًا،
But, on the other hand, if you are going to take drugs,
ولكن من ناحية أخرى، إن كنت تنوي تعاطي المخدرات،
you have a reasonably good way
فلديك طريقة معقولة وملائمة
of guaranteeing a certain level of purity and quality,
لضمان الحصول على مستوى معين من النقاء والجودة.
which is incredibly important if you're taking drugs.
وهو أمرٌ مهم لمن يتعاطى المخدرات.
And you can do so from the comfort of your own home,
يمكنك فعل ذلك وأنت مرتاح بمنزلك،
without the risks associated with buying on the streets.
دون المخاطرة المرتبطة بالشراء في الشوارع.
Now, as I said,
كما قلت،
you've got to be creative and innovative to survive in this marketplace.
عليك أن تكون مبدعًا ومبتكرًا لكي تبقى في هذا السوق.
And the 20 or so sites that are currently in operation --
والعشرون موقعًا أو الأكثر أو الأقل التي تعمل حاليًا
by the way, they don't always work, they're not always perfect;
على أي حال، فهي لا تعمل دائمًا، وليست مثالية دائمًا ،
the site that I showed you was shut down 18 months ago,
أُغلٍقت هذه المواقع التي عرضتها عليكم قبل 18 شهرًا،
but not before it had turned over a billion dollars' worth of trade.
لكن بعد أن جنت أكثر من مليار دولار قيمة التجارة.
But these markets,
ولكن هذه الأسواق،
because of the difficult conditions in which they are operating,
نتيجةً للظروف الصعبة التي تعمل فيها،
the inhospitable conditions,
-هذه الظروف عير الملائمة-
are always innovating, always thinking of ways of getting smarter,
دائمًا ما تكون هذه الأسواق مبتكِرة ومفكرةً في طرقٍ لتصبح أكثر نشاطًا
more decentralized, harder to censor,
وأقل مركزيةً، وأصعب مراقبةً،
and more customer-friendly.
وأكثر جاذبية للعملاء.
Let's take the payment system.
ولنتناول نظام الدفع
You don't pay with your credit card,
فأنت لا تدفع ببطاقة ائتمانك،
of course -- that would lead directly back to you.
-بالبطبع هذا يعود إليك في الأساس-
So you use the crypto-currency bitcoin,
لكنك تستخدم العملة المشفرة بيتكوين،
which is easily exchanged for real-world currencies
التي يسهل استبالها بالعملات الحقيقية
and gives quite a high degree of anonymity to its users.
وتمنح درجةً عالية من المجهولية لمستخدميها .
But at the beginning of these sites, people noticed a flaw.
لكن في بداية هذه المواقع، لاحظ الناس وجود عيبٍ ما.
Some of the unscrupulous dealers were running away with peoples' bitcoin
إذْ كان بعض التجار عديمي الضمير يهربون بعملات بينكوين الخاصة بالناس
before they'd mailed the drugs out.
قبل إرسال المخدرات إليهم.
The community came up with a solution, called multi-signature escrow payments.
توصل المجتمع إلى حلٍ يسمى مدفوعات الضمان متعددة التوقيع.
So on purchasing my item,
لذا عندما أشتري شيئًا ما،
I would send my bitcoin
سأرسل عملة بيتكوين خاصتي
to a neutral, secure third digital wallet.
إلى محفظة رقمية أخرى آمنة ومحايدة.
The vendor, who would see that I'd sent it,
سيصبح البائع -الذي سيرى أني أرسلت العملة-
would be confident that they could then send the product to me,
واثقا بأنهم يستطيعون إرسال المنتج إلي
and then when I received it,
وعندما أتسلمه،
at least two of the three people engaged in the transaction --
سيتعين على اثنين من أصل ثلاثة أشخاص اشتركوا في الصفقة
vendor, buyer, site administrator --
- هم البائع والمشتري، ومدير الموقع-
would have to sign the transaction off
سيتعين عليهم توقيع الصفقة
with a unique digital signature,
بتوقيع رقمي فريد،
and then the money would be transferred.
وبعدها سيُحول المبلغ.
Brilliant!
رائع!
Elegant.
ممتاز!
It works.
إنه يعمل.
But then they realized there was a problem with bitcoin,
ولكن أدركوا بعد ذلك أن ثمَّة مشكلة ما بعملة بيتكوين،
because every bitcoin transaction
لأن كل صفقة تتم بعملة البيتكوين
is actually recorded publicly in a public ledger.
تُسجل علنًا في دفتر حسابات عام.
So if you're clever, you can try and work out who's behind them.
لذا إن كنت ماهرًا، فيمكنك المحاولة واكتشاف من يقف خلفهم.
So they came up with a tumbling service.
لذا توصلوا إلى خدمة تقليب.
Hundreds of people send their bitcoin into one address,
يرسل مئات الناس عملات بيبتكوين خاصتهم إلى عنوان واحد،
they're tumbled and jumbled up,
ثم يُقلَبون ويُبعثَرون،
and then the right amount is sent on to the right recipients,
وبعد ذلك يُرسَل المبلغ الصحيح إلى المستلم الصحيح،
but they're different bitcoins:
ولكنها عملات بيتكوين مختلفة:
micro-laundering systems.
أنظمة غسيل مصغرة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's incredible.
هذا لا يصدق.
Interested in what drugs are trending right now on the dark net markets?
أتهتم بما تتجه إليه المخدرات حالياً في أسواق الشبكة المظلمة؟
Check Grams, the search engine.
تفحص محرك البحث (غرامز).
You can even buy some advertising space.
ويمكنك حتى شراء مساحة إعلانية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Are you an ethical consumer worried about what the drugs industry is doing?
أأنت مستهلك ذو خُلُق وتقلق بشأن ما تقوم به صناعة المخدرات؟
Yeah.
أجل.
One vendor will offer you fair trade organic cocaine.
سيعرض عليك أحد البائعين تجارة عادلة لكوكايين عضوي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
That's not being sourced from Colombian druglords,
ليس مصدره من ملك المخدرات الكولومبي،
but Guatemalan farmers.
بل المزارع الغواتيمالية.
They even promised to reinvest 20 percent of any profits
حتى إنهم وعدوا بإعادة استثمار حتى 20 % من الأرباح
into local education programs.
في البرامج التعليمية المحلية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
There's even a mystery shopper.
وحتى إنه يوجد متسوقٌ خفي.
Now, whatever you think about the morality of these sites --
والآن، أيًا كان ما تفكر به بشأن أخلاقية هذه المواقع
and I submit that it's not actually an easy question --
وأنا أُسلِم بأنه ليس سؤالاً سهلاً بالفعل
the creation of functioning, competitive, anonymous markets,
فخلق أسواق مهنية تنافسية خفية،
where nobody knows who anybody else is,
حيث لا يعلم أحدٌ من يكون الآخر،
constantly at risk of being shut down by the authorities,
ومواجهتها المستمرة لخطر غلق السلطات لها
is a staggering achievement,
هو إنجازٌ مذهل،
a phenomenal achievement.
إنجازٌ غير اعتيادي.
And it's that kind of innovation
وهذا النوع من الابتكار
that's why those on the fringes
هو السبب في أن هؤلاء المهمشين
are often the harbingers of what is to come.
غالبًا ما يتنبأون بالمستقبل.
It's easy to forget
ونظرًا لقصر عمر الإنترنت،
that because of its short life,
يسهل نسيان
the Internet has actually changed many times
أن الإنترنت قد تغير عدة مرات
over the last 30 years or so.
خلال الثلاثين عامًا الماضية أو أكثر.
It started in the '70s as a military project,
لقد بدأ في السبعينيات كمشروع عسكري،
morphed in the 1980s to an academic network,
وتحول في الثمانينيات إلى شبكة أكاديمية،
co-opted by commercial companies in the '90s,
ثم أدارته شركات تجارية في التسعينيات،
and then invaded by all of us via social media in the noughties,
وبعد ذلك غزوناه جميعًا عبر وسائط التواصل الاجتاعي في أوائل هذه الألفية
but I think it's going to change again.
ولكني أعتقد أنه سيتغير مجددًا.
And I think things like the dark net markets --
وأعتقد بأن أشياءً مثل أسواق الشبكة المظلمة
creative, secure, difficult to censor --
الإبداعية الآمنة التي يصعب مراقبتها
I think that's the future.
أعتقد أنها هي المستقبل.
And the reason it's the future
والسبب في أنها هي المستقبل
is because we're all worried about our privacy.
هو أننا جميعًا نقلق بشأن خصوصيتنا.
Surveys consistently show concerns about privacy.
تُظهر الاستطلاعات بصورة منتظمة اهتمامات بشأن الخصوصية.
The more time we spend online, the more we worry about them,
فكلما زاد الوقت الذي نقضيه على الإنترنت، زاد قلقنا بشأن خصوصياتنا،
and those surveys show our worries are growing.
وتُظهر هذه الدراسات أن قلقنا في تزايد.
We're worried about what happens to our data.
فنحن نقلق بشأن ما يحدث لبياناتنا.
who might be watching us.
ونقلق بشأن من قد يكون يراقبنا.
Since the revelations from Edward Snowden,
منذ تسريبات (إدوارد سنودن)
there's been a huge increase in the number of people
يوجد ازدياد كبير في عدد الناس
using various privacy-enhancing tools.
المستخدمين لأدوات تعزيز الخصوصية المتنوعة.
There are now between two and three million daily users
فثمَّة الآن حوالي اثنين إلى ثلاثة ملايين مستخدم يوميًا
of the Tor browser,
يستخدمون متصفح (تور)،
the majority of which use is perfectly legitimate,
وغالبية استخداماته شرعية تمامًا،
sometimes even mundane.
وبسيطة أحيانًا.
And there are hundreds of activists around the world
ويوجد مئات من النشطاء حول العالم
working on techniques and tools to keep you private online --
يعملون على أساليب وأدوات تحافظ على خصوصيتكم على الإنترنت
default encrypted messaging services.
مثل خدمات الرسائل المشفرة الافتراضية.
Ethereum, which is a project which tries to link up
(إيثيريوم)، وهو مشروع يحاول ربط
the connected but unused hard drives of millions of computers around the world,
الأقراص الصلبة المتصلة غير المستعلمة لملايين الحواسيب حول العالم،
to create a sort of distributed Internet that no one really controls.
لخلق نوع من الإنترنت الموزع لا يتحكم فيه أحد.
Now, we've had distributed computing before, of course.
وحاليًا، لدينا حوسبة موزعة مسبقًا بطبيعة الحال.
We use it for everything from Skype to the search for extraterrestrial life.
تُستخدم في كل شيء بدءًا من سكايب وانتهاءً بالبحث عن الحياة خارج الأرض.
But you add distributed computing and powerful encryption --
لكنكم تضيفون حوسبة موزعة وتشفير قوي-
that's very, very hard to censor and control.
تصعب جدًا مراقبتها والتحكم فيها.
Another called MaidSafe works on similar principles.
وأخرى تُسمى (ميدسيف) .تعمل على الأسس نفسها.
Another called Twister, and so on and so on.
وأخرى تُدعى (تويستر)، وهلم جرًا.
And here's the thing --
وهذا هو الأمر--
the more of us join,
فكلما انضم الكثير منا،
the more interesting those sites become,
أصبحت هذه المواقع أكثر إثارة،
and then the more of us join, and so on.
ومن ثم ينضم المزيد منا، وهكذا.
And I think that's what's going to happen.
وأعتقد أن هذا هو ما سيحدث.
In fact, it's already happening.
في الواقع، إنه يحدث بالفعل.
The dark net is no longer a den for dealers
لم تعُد الشبكة المظلمة وكرًا للتجار
and a hideout for whistle-blowers.
وملجأً لكاشفي الفساد
It's already going mainstream.
فهي تسير بالفعل في الاتجاه السائد.
Just recently, the musician Aphex Twin released his album as a dark net site.
مؤخرًا، أصدر الموسيقار (أفيكس توين) ألبومًا له على أنه موقع شبكة مظلمة
Facebook has started a dark net site.
أسس (الفيسبوك) موقع شبكة مظلمة.
A group of London architects have opened a dark net site
اقتتح مجموعة من المهندسين المعماريين اللندنيين موقع شبكة مظلمة.
for people worried about regeneration projects.
لأجل الأشخاص الذين يقلقون بشأن مشروعات التجديد.
Yes, the dark net is going mainstream,
نعم، تسير الشبكة المظلمة في الاتجاه السائد،
and I predict that fairly soon, every social media company,
وأتنبأ أنه في القريب العاجل، ستسخدم شركات التواصل الاجتماعي،
every major news outlet,
وكل منفذ إخباري رائد،
and therefore most of you in this audience,
ومِن ثَمَّ معظم هذا الجمهور،
will be using the dark net, too.
الشبكة المظلمة أيضًا.
So the Internet is about to get more interesting,
لذا فالإنترنت على وشك أن يصبح أكثر تشويقًا،
more exciting, more innovative,
وأكثر إثارةً، وأكثر إبتكارًا،
more terrible,
وأكثر فظاعةً
more destructive.
وأكثر تدميرًا.
That's good news if you care about liberty.
وهذه أخبارق سارة إذا كنت تهتم بالتحرر.
It's good news if you care about freedom.
وهي أخبارٌ سارة إن كنت تهتم بالحرية.
It's good news if you care about democracy.
وهي أخبارٌ سارة إن كنت تهتم بالديمقراطية.
It's also good news
كما أنها أخبارٌ سارة
if you want to browse for illegal pornography
إن كنت ترغب في تصفح المواد الإباحية غير القانونية
and if you want to buy and sell drugs
وإن كنت ترغب في شراء وبيع المخدرات
with impunity.
دون خشية العقوبة.
Neither entirely dark, nor entirely light.
سواءً أكان الإنترنت مظلمًا تمامًا أو مضيئا تمامًا.
It's not one side or the other that's going to win out, but both.
ليس جانبًا واحدًا أو الآخر هو الذي سينجح، بل الاثنين معًا.
Thank you very much, indeed.
شكرًا جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)